eagles.org 2018-08-29

# Privacy Policy – American Eagle Foundation

Your privacy is important to the American Eagle Foundation (“we” or “us”). This privacy practices statement (“Privacy Policy”) applies to the American Eagle Foundation website [www.eagles.org](https://www.eagles.org/) (the “Website”) and is designed to explain what types of information is gathered, tracked and how this information is used. Please note that this Privacy Policy does not apply to third party websites (“Third Party Services”) that the American Eagle Foundation does not control, including, but not limited to Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest, Instagram and Google+, even if you access them through the Website. It also does not apply to any Third Party Services embedded on our website (such as Chatroll, live-streaming webcams). While we try to only work with Third Party Services that share our respect for your privacy, we cannot take responsibility for their practices, content, or privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully review the privacy policies of any Third Party Services you access so that you know how they will use and share your information. Additionally, this Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of people that the American Eagle Foundation does not employ or manage. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by the Website.

We encourage you to read this Privacy Policy before using the Website. By accessing and/or using the Website, you agree to the terms, use, disclosure, and procedures of this Privacy Policy. As the terms of this Privacy Policy may be amended from time to time, please do not use the Website if you disagree with any part of this Privacy Policy. As we update and/or expand our services and products, this Privacy Policy may change, so check back to this page from time to time. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into, and part of the Terms of Use located at: www.eagles.org/terms-of-use/ (“Terms of Use”), which governs your access and use of the Website, including any Content, as defined in the Terms of Use.

If you are unsure whether this Privacy Policy is in conflict with the applicable local laws where you are located, you should not submit your or any other person’s personally identifiably information to us. Anyone who accesses, uses or interacts with us. including, but not limited to providing sensitive information does affirmatively consent to the collection, use and sharing of such information, including personally identifiably information, as provided in and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

### Introduction

The Website aims to educate the public about Bald Eagles and birds-of-prey, to inform Website visitors about our education, rehabilitation, repopulation, and conservation programs, and to raise money for our programs through merchandise sales and donations. The Website sometimes requests and collects personal information from site visitors. This Privacy Policy discloses the privacy practices for www.eagles.org.

### Information Collection

The American Eagle Foundation is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. We only have access to and collect information that is voluntarily provided to us by email, newsletter subscription, website usage, account registration, purchases, donations, memberships, adoptions, or other direct contact from you.

We will use your information for internal purposes, for contacting you in relation to the reason(s) that your information was provided, or to share news and updates with you about the American Eagle Foundation.

You may use the Website to learn about our products and services without disclosing any personal information. We may also provide a more typical registration process where you may be required to provide us with contact information, such as your first and last name, home, business and email addresses, telephone, mobile and facsimile numbers, type of business, and certain other information about you or your business.

On the Website, you may be able to sign up to receive electronic newsletters and promotional emails from us. To sign up, we may ask you for information such as your name, email address, postal address, telephone number, age, gender, shopping preferences and email preferences. You may also sign up to submit comments and your name to blogs we host on the Website. If you communicate with us through the “Contact” link on the Website, we may ask you for information such as your name and you and/or your company’s name, email address, zip code and telephone number.

We do not sell or rent personal information to third parties.

Unless you ask us not to, we may contact you by email in the future to tell you about news topics, promotions, new products, or changes to this Privacy Policy.

### Registration

In order to use some portions of this website, a user may first be required to register for a user account. During registration, a user is required to give certain information (such as name and email address). This information is used for internal record-keeping purposes, for contacting you in relation to the reason your information was provided, or to share news and updates with you about the American Eagle Foundation.

### Orders

We request information from you during the purchasing process. To buy from us, you must provide contact information (such as name and shipping address) and financial information (such as credit card number and expiration date). This information is used for billing purposes and to fill your orders. If we have trouble processing an order, we will use this information to contact you.

### Cookies

We may use “cookies” on this site. A cookie is a piece of data stored on a site visitor’s hard drive to help us improve your access to our site and identify repeat visitors to our site. For instance, when we use a cookie to identify you, you would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our site. Cookies can also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site.

You can set your browser to alert you when a cookie is being used, and accept or reject the cookie. You can also set your browser to refuse all cookies or accept only cookies returned to the originating servers. Users can generally disable the cookie feature on their browser without affecting their ability to use the Website, except in some cases where cookies are used as an essential security feature necessary for transaction completion. Cookies, however, are important to the proper functioning of a website, and disabling them may degrade your experience and interfere with the Website’s features and customizations.

We may use Flash cookies, also known as “local shared objects,” on our Websites that employ Flash technology. Flash cookies are used to remember the Website’s settings to personalize the look and feel of the Website. Like normal cookies, Flash cookies are represented as small files on your computer. One method of preventing Flash cookies from being placed is to adjust your preferences in the Macromedia Website Privacy Settings Panel at macromedia.com.

### Embedded URLs

The American Eagle Foundation may use a tracking technique that employs embedded URLs to allow use of the Website without cookies. Embedded URLs allow limited information to follow you as you navigate the Website, but are not associated with personal information and are not used beyond the session

Embedded Pixels and Similar Technology

On the Website, the American Eagle Foundation and its service providers may use embedded pixel technologies for the purposes of identifying unique user visits (as opposed to aggregate hits), and for advertising purposes. In addition, embedded pixels or other technologies may be used in emails and our online display advertising to provide information on when the email or ad was opened to track marketing campaign responsiveness; information collected using these technologies may be associated with the recipient’s email address.

### Interactive Widgets

The Website may include widgets, which are interactive mini-programs that run on our Services to provide specific services from another company (e.g., links to bookmarked sites), along with buttons or other tools that link to other companies’ services (e.g., a “Like” button or third party map). The widget, button or tool may collect and automatically send personal information, such as your email address, or other information (such as your browser information, or IP address), to a third party. Cookies may also be set or used by the widgets, buttons or tools to enable them to function properly or for other purposes, which may include advertising. Information collected or used by a widget, button or tool, including cookie settings and preferences, is governed by the privacy policy of the company that created it. We have no responsibility or liability for the practices, policies and security measures implemented by such third parties.

### Location Based Services

We may collect, use, and share the physical location of your device and use it to provide you with personalized location-based services or content. Where available, location-based services may use GPS, Bluetooth, and your IP Address, along with crowd-sourced Wi-Fi hotspot and cell tower locations, and other technologies to determine your devices’ approximate location. In some instances, you may be permitted to allow or deny such use of your device’s location, but if you choose to deny such use, we may not be able to provide you with the applicable personalized services or content.

### Web Analytic Services

We also may use third party web analytics services, such as Google Analytics, to measure the effectiveness of our advertising and determine how visitors use the Website. These service providers’ tools, including cookies, web server logs and web beacons, allow us to collect information such as the state and zip code from which our visitors come and the IP addresses of our visitors’ computers. You can opt out of aggregation and analysis of data collected by Google Analytics at https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.

### Other Ways We Collect Information

We also may obtain information that you have made publicly or lawfully available, such as, by social media posts, or information provided by third party sources, such as marketing opt-in lists, data aggregators and our third party providers. In addition, we may supplement information you give us by the Website with information from other sources, such as information validating your email address or other available information about you or your business.

### How We Use Information

The American Eagle Foundation uses the information we collect from you for the following purposes:

  * Provide products and services to you;
  * send you promotional materials and other communications;
  *  communicate with you about, and administer your participation in, special events, contests, sweepstakes, programs, offers, and surveys;
  * provide information to you about our products and services in accordance with this Privacy Policy;
  *  tailor your use of the Website and communications according to your preferences and our terms;
  *  respond to your inquiries;
  *  create and manage your account on the Website;
  * operate, evaluate and improve our business (including developing new products and services; enhancing and improving the Website (for example, to facilitate navigation and the login process, avoid duplicate data entry, enhance security and keep track of shopping cart additions and information between sessions); managing our communications; analyzing our products, services and viewer base; performing data analytics; (including email marketing), and performing accounting, auditing and other internal functions);
  * verify your identity;
  * contact or notify you, if necessary;
  * protect the security or integrity of the Website;
  * protect against, identify and prevent fraud and other unlawful activity, claims and other liabilities; and
  * comply with and enforce applicable legal requirements, our Terms of Use, relevant industry standards, contractual obligations and our policies.

### Information We Share

We do not sell or otherwise disclose personal information about you, except as described in this Privacy Policy. We may share the information with our service providers who perform services on our behalf based on our instructions. These service providers are not authorized by us to use or disclose the information except as necessary to perform services on our behalf or comply with legal requirements. Examples of these service providers include entities that verify information, fulfill orders, and provide web hosting, analytics and marketing services.

We also may disclose information about you (i) if we are required to do so by law or legal process (such as a court order); (ii) in response to a request by law enforcement authorities; (iii) enforce our Terms of Use or the terms of any of our statements or policies; or (iv) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity. We also reserve the right to transfer personal information we have about you in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets (including in the event of a reorganization, dissolution or liquidation). Should such a sale or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to direct the transferee to use personal information you have provided to us in a manner that is consistent with our then-current Privacy Policy. Following such a sale or transfer, you may contact the entity to which we transferred your personal information with any inquiries concerning the processing of that information.

### Your Access to and Control Over Information

You may opt out of any future contacts from us at any time. You can do the following at any time:

  * Review what information we have collected from you, if any.
  * Change/correct any information that we have collected from you.
  * Request that we delete any information we have collected from you.
  * Express any concern you have about our use of your information.

### Security

We take precautions to protect your information. When you submit sensitive information by the website, your information is protected both online and offline.

Wherever we collect sensitive information (such as credit card data), that information is encrypted and transmitted to us in a secure way. Full credit card information is not stored on our server, but is used, and may be stored by, the third-party merchant services we use to process merchandise sales and giving (donations, adoptions, memberships, etc.)

While we use encryption to protect sensitive information transmitted online, we also protect your information offline. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job function (for example, billing or customer service) are granted access to personally identifiable information.

Although we endeavor to protect the security and integrity of personal information collected by the Website, due to the inherent nature of the Internet as an open global communications vehicle, we cannot guarantee that any information, during transmission through the Internet or while stored on our system or otherwise in our care, will be absolutely safe from intrusion by others, such as hackers. If you correspond with us by email, text message, or using Web forms like a “contact us” feature on the Website, you should be aware that your transmission might not be secure. A third party could view the information you send in transit by such means. We will have no liability for disclosure of your information due to errors or unauthorized acts of third parties. If we believe that the security of your personal information in our care may have been compromised, we may seek to notify you of that development. If a notification is appropriate, we will endeavor to notify you as promptly as possible under the circumstances. If we have your email address, we may notify you by email. You consent to our use of email as a means of such notification. If you prefer for us to use the U.S. Postal Service to notify you in this situation, please email us at eaglemail@eagles.org.

### Links

This web site may contain links to other sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of any other site that collects personally identifiable information.

### Contests, Surveys & Promotions

From time-to-time our site requests information for contests, surveys, or promotions. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you may choose whether or not to participate and therefore disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code and age level). Contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes. Survey information may be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site.

### Children

Although we may choose to offer a Kid’s Membership level, the Website is not directed to children under the age of thirteen (13) and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of thirteen (13) on the Website. If we become aware that we have inadvertently received personal information from a child under the age of thirteen (13) on our Website without a parent or guardian’s consent, we will delete the information from our records; provided that such access is not unreasonably burdensome or expensive under the circumstances. Our Children’s Privacy Policy is located [here](https://www.eagles.org/coppa/). We recommend that prospective users between the ages of thirteen (13) and seventeen (17) ask their parents or other legal guardians for permission before sending any information about themselves to anyone over the Internet. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child under the age of thirteen (13) has provided us with information without their consent, he or she should contact us at eaglemail@eagles.org In addition, we reserve the right to limit participation to visitors eighteen (18) years of age, twenty one (21) years of age, or older.

### Updates

We retain the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time and without prior notice to you to reflect changes in the American Eagle Foundation’s personal information practices or relevant laws. The practices and policies contained in this Privacy Policy replace all previous notices or statements with respect to the same subject. Your access, use or interaction with us or the Website following the posting of such changes or the updated Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of any such changes. We encourage you to review our Privacy Policy frequently to make sure that you understand how we collect and use.

### Privacy Policy Effective Date

This Privacy Policy is effective May 2016.

Scroll to top
